<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>intro &#8211; TMR</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/myblog/tag/intro/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Liberal + Christian Blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:52:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Mossy Rock Collecting Dirt</title>
		<link>/2020/04/14/mossy-rock-collecting-dirt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mdrez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 04:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[About Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mossy rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no one is perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quaranblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quarantine blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=60</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello! As many of us, I have a lot of extra time due to quarantine and have decided to start a blog. I&#8217;m hoping this will help me out with a lot of anxiety and depression I&#8217;m going through, and maybe in turn can help others going through similar struggles.<a class="moretag" href="/2020/04/14/mossy-rock-collecting-dirt/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello!</p>



<p>As many of us, I have a lot of extra time due to quarantine and have decided to start a blog.  I&#8217;m hoping this will help me out with a lot of anxiety and depression I&#8217;m going through, and maybe in turn can help others going through similar struggles.</p>



<p>Who Am I?</p>



<p>My name is Monica and I&#8217;m a Web Developer living in Denver, Colorado.  This WordPress is a test of my ability to let go of control, and not just die when all the CSS isn&#8217;t perfect.  I moved here from Austin, Texas 2 years ago to work at a video game company.  My interests include board games, video games, t-rexes (my husband proposed in an inflatable t-rex costume), and my dog Simon.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-82" width="497" height="497" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /><figcaption><em>Simon is a very good boy&#8230; why is this caption not center aligned? I don&#8217;t know, probably because WordPress knows it will drive me crazy.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>I&#8217;m also extremely liberal and a Christian.  These two things are often thought of as opposites, but I see them as going hand in hand. That&#8217;s something I would like to explore here as I expand what it means to me to be Christ-like, walk with Jesus, and love thy neighbors.</p>



<p>Why The Mossy Rock?</p>



<p>When my (now) husband was deciding if he wanted to date me or not, he apparently had a conversation with his mother about me.  He wasn&#8217;t sure if I was The One, which was providing a lot of inner conflict if he should even start the dating process.  I didn&#8217;t exactly fit in with his image of a perfect partner in many ways.  &#8220;If she&#8217;s not The One, why bother even dating?&#8221; he pondered.</p>



<p>My now Second Mother (we don&#8217;t like using in-law, it sounds too formal!) listened to her son&#8217;s woes and told him this metaphor.  Say you have a perfect white cube.  It&#8217;s perfect and stainless and white.  Then say you have a rock.  And this rock is mossy and dented and has some dirt here and there.  Which one is more interesting to look at and analyze and spend time with and get to know?</p>



<p>Lucky for me, my husband chose the rock.</p>



<p>After he told me this story, the image of the Mossy Rock really resonated with me.  I&#8217;m not a perfect white cube (I really don&#8217;t think anyone is to be honest).  I have a lot of flaws and I&#8217;m working through a lot of things.  And that&#8217;s okay.  My imperfections make me human and real.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m hoping this blog can provide a spot for me to share my journey and struggles, my beliefs and my questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
