<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>quarantine blog &#8211; TMR</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/myblog/tag/quarantine-blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Liberal + Christian Blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:33:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Coming Out Christian</title>
		<link>/2020/04/15/coming-out-christian/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mdrez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[About Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[about me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homosexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liberal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open-minded]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quaranblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quarantine blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=95</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trying to come up with a name for this blog post, I Google searched &#8220;liberal synonyms&#8221; so maybe I could stop writing the same word over and over. Synonyms include tolerant, unprejudiced, unbigoted, open-minded, progressive, advanced, and forward-looking. These are definitely words I strive for and would love if people<a class="moretag" href="/2020/04/15/coming-out-christian/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Trying to come up with a name for this blog post, I Google searched &#8220;liberal synonyms&#8221; so maybe I could stop writing the same word over and over.  Synonyms include tolerant, unprejudiced, unbigoted, open-minded, progressive, advanced, and forward-looking.  These are definitely words I strive for and would love if people used to describe me.  I might not always be successful, but I never want to be the opposite of those words.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why, I believe, a lot of my friends were thrown off guard when I came out as a Christian.</p>



<p>As a hippy-dippy, Democrat voting, left-wing nut liberal, this was unexpected.  The Christian community has grown into a monolith of right-wing ideals.  Christian people are often anti-LGBTQ+ and anti-progress and anti-science.  What was I doing getting mixed in with those sorts of people?</p>



<p>It really comes down to the Bible, God, and Jesus.</p>



<p>Throughout my life, I had a mixed relationship with churches and Christianity.  Growing up, we were CEO Christians (Christmas Easter Only).  My high school boyfriend brought me to church with him and I learned that churches not only were open every Sunday, but also there were events and activities throughout the week that church goers did together.</p>



<p>I stopped going to church, largely because of the church&#8217;s views on homosexuality.  I have many queer friends and consider myself a part of the queer community.  I have never felt more at home in any group of people.  How can I be a part of a group that so openly makes these people feel like less?</p>



<p>Much later in life, I began interpreting (I&#8217;m a certified ASL interpreter) for a church every Sunday.  I would meet with my fellow interpreters and we would analyze the service and find the best signs to fit.  Unexpectedly, I was learning about the Bible.  It wasn&#8217;t until I stopped interpreting at this church that I began to really miss and yearn for those Bible study meetings, even though at the time I hadn&#8217;t realized that was what we were doing.</p>



<p>I had a small medical scare that really shook me and, as if on instinct, I prayed about it.  After results came in and I was completely fine, I realized that it was a bit messed up that I only reached out to God when I needed something.  I decided to start going to church again and see where that lead me.</p>



<p>I went to a few churches and saw again what I had seen when I left the church: close-minded people.  I then decided to do more research.  If these people were right, and the Bible really is anti-homosexuality, then the Bible is not for me.  I have a fundamental belief and knowledge that being gay is not a choice and that there is nothing wrong with two people of the same sex being in a consensual relationship.  If the Bible disagrees with this, it must be wrong and this whole Christianity thing is wrong.</p>



<p>I have news, friends &#8211; the Bible is NOT anti-homosexuality!</p>



<p>I know, shocker.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to explore this more in depth in future posts, but after really reading and analyzing all the Bible verses Christians have used to be anti-LGBTQ+, I honestly believe that those Christians are wrong.  They&#8217;re using the Bible just as racists have used it for white supremacy.  They&#8217;re making choices and picking words from here and there to fit with a preconceived idea that has been passed down to them.</p>



<p>I believe God took me on my specific path so that I could see and know the truth.  If I had grown up in the church, I would be just as blinded to this idea as many of my Christian friends.  Because of where I come from, I can see and read and interpret The Word without the biases of my ancestors.</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re still here and I haven&#8217;t completely scared you off, I really hope you&#8217;ll join me as I go through the &#8220;6 Bullets&#8221; Christians use against homosexuality.  We&#8217;ll explore the Bible, God&#8217;s words, and why these interpretations align more with the overall words of Jesus.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mossy Rock Collecting Dirt</title>
		<link>/2020/04/14/mossy-rock-collecting-dirt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mdrez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 04:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[About Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hello world]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mossy rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no one is perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quaranblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quarantine blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=60</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello! As many of us, I have a lot of extra time due to quarantine and have decided to start a blog. I&#8217;m hoping this will help me out with a lot of anxiety and depression I&#8217;m going through, and maybe in turn can help others going through similar struggles.<a class="moretag" href="/2020/04/14/mossy-rock-collecting-dirt/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hello!</p>



<p>As many of us, I have a lot of extra time due to quarantine and have decided to start a blog.  I&#8217;m hoping this will help me out with a lot of anxiety and depression I&#8217;m going through, and maybe in turn can help others going through similar struggles.</p>



<p>Who Am I?</p>



<p>My name is Monica and I&#8217;m a Web Developer living in Denver, Colorado.  This WordPress is a test of my ability to let go of control, and not just die when all the CSS isn&#8217;t perfect.  I moved here from Austin, Texas 2 years ago to work at a video game company.  My interests include board games, video games, t-rexes (my husband proposed in an inflatable t-rex costume), and my dog Simon.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-82" width="497" height="497" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme.jpg 600w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme-300x300.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2020/04/aboutme-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 497px) 100vw, 497px" /><figcaption><em>Simon is a very good boy&#8230; why is this caption not center aligned? I don&#8217;t know, probably because WordPress knows it will drive me crazy.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>I&#8217;m also extremely liberal and a Christian.  These two things are often thought of as opposites, but I see them as going hand in hand. That&#8217;s something I would like to explore here as I expand what it means to me to be Christ-like, walk with Jesus, and love thy neighbors.</p>



<p>Why The Mossy Rock?</p>



<p>When my (now) husband was deciding if he wanted to date me or not, he apparently had a conversation with his mother about me.  He wasn&#8217;t sure if I was The One, which was providing a lot of inner conflict if he should even start the dating process.  I didn&#8217;t exactly fit in with his image of a perfect partner in many ways.  &#8220;If she&#8217;s not The One, why bother even dating?&#8221; he pondered.</p>



<p>My now Second Mother (we don&#8217;t like using in-law, it sounds too formal!) listened to her son&#8217;s woes and told him this metaphor.  Say you have a perfect white cube.  It&#8217;s perfect and stainless and white.  Then say you have a rock.  And this rock is mossy and dented and has some dirt here and there.  Which one is more interesting to look at and analyze and spend time with and get to know?</p>



<p>Lucky for me, my husband chose the rock.</p>



<p>After he told me this story, the image of the Mossy Rock really resonated with me.  I&#8217;m not a perfect white cube (I really don&#8217;t think anyone is to be honest).  I have a lot of flaws and I&#8217;m working through a lot of things.  And that&#8217;s okay.  My imperfections make me human and real.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m hoping this blog can provide a spot for me to share my journey and struggles, my beliefs and my questions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
