<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Leviticus &#8211; TMR</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/myblog/tag/leviticus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>Liberal + Christian Blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 02:15:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Next Up: Leviticus</title>
		<link>/2020/07/23/next-up-leviticus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mdrez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 02:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leviticus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quaranblog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quarantine blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Bible]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trigger Warnings: Pedophilia. Phew, this one I believe is the hardest for many people, myself included. It&#8217;s the only one I don&#8217;t feel that there is one &#8220;right&#8221; answer, there are many alternative answers, and I can&#8217;t in good faith deduce which one feels the most accurate. Of course, with<a class="moretag" href="/2020/07/23/next-up-leviticus/"> Read more&#8230;</a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Trigger Warnings: Pedophilia.</p>



<p>Phew, this one I believe is the hardest for many people, myself included.  It&#8217;s the only one I don&#8217;t feel that there is one &#8220;right&#8221; answer, there are many alternative answers, and I can&#8217;t in good faith deduce which one feels the most accurate.</p>



<p>Of course, with all these passage interpretations, there is no &#8220;right&#8221; answer at all.  I used to work as a sign language interpreter and let me tell you something &#8211; there is no single right interpretation of anything, let alone ancient texts.  I believe that scholars and historians and religious study professors are all doing their best to interpret The Word as accurately as possible, but they have one flaw they can&#8217;t get around &#8211; they&#8217;re human! And I am too!  No matter what, we are interpreting these texts through our own flawed and judgmental reality, with all our privileges and biases and life experiences behind those interpretations.</p>



<p>With that being said, why should anyone care about my interpretation of the Bible? Well, I believe I have a unique perspective in the fact that I wasn&#8217;t raised in the church.  This lets me weed out and see through a lot of things many people raised in the church deem as &#8220;facts&#8221; that are really just interpretations.  I <span class="has-inline-color has-black-color">believe </span>my outsider perspective is valuable and different to many voices prevalent in the Christian community.  I think my time as an interpreter, my time as an agnostic, and my journey to find truth have put me in a unique position to share my findings.</p>



<p>But really, I think everyone&#8217;s journey is unique and different, and I just hope that my own journey can help someone else on theirs.</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s get into Leviticus!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><sup>22&nbsp;</sup>“‘Do not have sexual relations with a man as one does with a woman;&nbsp;that is detestable.</p><cite>Leviticus 18:22&nbsp;New International Version (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><sup>13&nbsp;</sup>“‘If a man has sexual relations with a man as one does with a woman, both of them have done what is detestable.&nbsp;They are to be put to death; their blood will be on their own heads.</p><cite>Leviticus 20:13&nbsp;New International Version (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>Yikes, right?  So many people have used these lines to justify hate, discrimination, and even murder.  On the surface, this appears straightforward and to the point.  But really, it&#8217;s anything but.</p>



<p>As Adam Nicholas Phillips points out in his fantastic article &#8220;<em>The Bible Does Not Condemn Homosexuality. Why Does Franklin Graham Not Get This?</em>&#8220;, the Leviticus commandments were written for a people that were on the run out of Egypt.  They were written at a very specific time for a very specific people.</p>



<p>That said, I still believe the Bible was written so vague and without direct points for exactly the purpose that it would be timeless.  If the Bible was written with explicit and direct &#8220;how-to&#8217;s&#8221;, there would be no humanity.  The vagueness is &#8220;sorta what God is going for&#8221;, to quote <em>The Book of Mormon</em>, the musical.  It&#8217;s vague so it can be understood and interpreted for all time periods by all peoples.</p>



<p>So, with the thought that the Bible is timeless, it doesn&#8217;t matter who Leviticus was written for, it should all still apply now.  Correct?</p>



<p>Well, not quite.  Leviticus is also where the Bible forbids eating shellfish (11:9-12), promotes slavery (25:44-45), and describes how you cannot wear mixed fabric (19:19). Look at that shirt you&#8217;re wearing and let me know how well you&#8217;re following those Leviticus commandments.</p>



<p>We can all see plainly with our eyes that slavery is bad.  We can all see that wearing mixed fabrics or eating shellfish is not something Jesus thought was important to uphold and maintain.  Jesus is the fulfilment of this law.  Jesus spoke often and frequently how there were many people &#8220;upholding the law&#8221; but finding loopholes and still being greedy and selfish.  That was more important to focus on &#8211; being good, loving others, helping the poor.  That was what Jesus preached about and spoke for.  Your attitude and intention are what is important.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><sup>38&nbsp;</sup>“You have heard that it was said, ‘Eye for eye, and tooth for tooth.’&nbsp;<sup>39&nbsp;</sup>But I tell you, do not resist an evil person. If anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to them the other cheek also.&nbsp;<sup>40&nbsp;</sup>And if anyone wants to sue you and take your shirt, hand over your coat as well.&nbsp;<sup>41&nbsp;</sup>If anyone forces you to go one mile, go with them two miles.&nbsp;<sup>42&nbsp;</sup>Give to the one who asks you, and do not turn away from the one who wants to borrow from you.</p><cite>Matthew 5:38-42&nbsp;New International Version (NIV)</cite></blockquote>



<p>In many ways, Jesus came to focus our attention on what we were doing wrong.  And focusing on shellfish and mixed fabrics was not one of those things.  Why then do people pluck this single passage and deem it more important than any others in Leviticus?</p>



<p>I have also seen in multiple sources how this passage is most likely completely mistranslated all together!  In the article &#8220;<em>Redefining Leviticus 20:13</em>&#8220;, it explains how the specific Hebrew words are more likely in reference to an adult man and a young man.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><sup>22&nbsp;</sup>Thou shalt not lie with zachar, as with isha: it is to’evah (abomination, detestable)</p><cite>Vayikra 18:22&nbsp;Orthodox Jewish Bible (OJB)</cite></blockquote>



<p>Aka, this passage is explaining specifically how pedophilia is wrong.  An adult man should not have sex with a young boy.  This falls perfectly in line with my core belief that &#8220;sexual sin&#8221; is when sex is used to hurt or harm someone, such as a child.  Sexual sin is not a reference to two consensual adults loving each other in marriage.</p>



<p>It likely was completely changed due to Emperor Constantine&#8217;s anti-homosexual laws.  Emperor Constantine ruled from AD 306 and 337 and already the Bible was being translated and change to fit in with what he deemed as accurate.</p>



<p>Why would my interpretation be more accurate than his interpretation?  It follows the overall narrative of the Bible to be loving and kind and to not hate your neighbor.  It truly falls in line with Jesus&#8217;s preaching and His message.</p>



<p>There is no sin in a man loving and being in a consensual relationship with another man.  At least not according to Leviticus.  We have 4 more passages to go and I hope you stay with me to learn more!</p>



<p>Resources:</p>



<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/the-bible-does-not-condemn-homosexuality_b_7807342" target="_blank">The Bible Does Not Condemn Homosexuality. Why Does Franklin Graham Not Get This?</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://jewishstandard.timesofisrael.com/redefining-leviticus-2013/" target="_blank">Redefining Leviticus 20:13</a></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
